JAMES PORTER

MANAGER / HOSPITALITY PROFESSIONAL / FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

A hospitality professional with 13 years in the filed, i have managed teams of up to 80 personnel while coordinating security and other event aspects for foreign presidents, entertainment industry CEOs, famous performers and more.

Meanwhile, i graduated UCLA's Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp, building three fuil stack applications with functionality to aid in commercial business organization and complex travel arrangements. Full Stack apps built in particular with React are my primary interest.

NOTABLE SKILLS

- MS Office Suite Particularly Excel
- VBA, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript & REACT
- Copy writing & editing
- Personnel management & client relations
- Payroll Management
- Staff recruitment, training & discipline
- Workplace policy formulation implementation
- Client onboarding & project budgeting

CONTACT DETAILS

Los Angeles, CA 90064 United States

https://james-porterfullstack.firebaseapp.com/

porterjjamesucla@gmail.com

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles -Class of 2016 Bachelor of Arts: Political Science

University of California, Los Angeles Extension February, 2023

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp Certificate

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Patron Services Manager - Royce Hall, UCLA Los Angeles, C.A., March 2018 - Current

Manage a Front of House team of roughly 70 employees serving tens of thousands of theater patrons per year

Oversee revenue sharing relationship & day-to-day operations of venue's Concessionaire

Organize and oversee parking arrangements for 1800 guests Coordinate and manage client merchandise sales Field patron phone calls, complaints, & incident resolution include public relations copy and one on one external communications

Coordinate security for an 1800 seat theater & high level VIP's Track and manage invoicing and budgeting for Front of House, Security and Parking services for each individual event

Fellow - Researcher / Coordinator, Propper Daley

Los Angeles, C.A., May 2017 - December 2017 Conducted landscape analysis for clients & strategy team Composed client press releases for Paramount, Universal Studios and more

Created social media press language for multiple organizations Created back- end inventory management and digital assets for 2017 Call of Duty Race to Prestige

Lead House Manager, Geffen Playhouse

Los Angeles, C.A., November 2015 - March 2018
Organize usher staff & Oversee theater operation
Administer merchandise sales

Liaise with VIP's such as Tom Hanks, Dave Chappelle, Morgan Freeman, etc.

Lobbyist / Publication Editor / Researcher, UCLA Student Los Angeles, C.A., September 2014 - June 2016 Orchestrated UCLA Student Government lobbying trips to Washington D.C., managing over 200 congressional meetings in a week long period. Was a publication editor for UCLA Political Science Student Organization. Conducted original 5,000 word research into global nuclear non- proliferation regimes.

661-810-5155